Finding Aid for Gerhard L. Weinberg papers, 1957-1973
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Gerhard L. Weinberg papers 1957-1973
Weinberg, Gerhard L.
7 linear feet and 1 phonograph record
86288 Aa 2
Professor of history at University of Michigan; Democratic Party files and records of his University of Michigan activities.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Gerhard L. Weinberg (donor no. 5522 ).
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Gerhard L. Weinberg was a professor of German history at the University of Michigan and the University of North Carolina, Chapel Hill. While in Ann Arbor, Weinberg was involved with the local Democratic Party, serving as chairman of the Ann Arbor, Michigan Democratic Party and as member of the Democratic Party State Central Committee and the state Democratic Party Reform Commission.
The Gerhard L. Weinberg collection is comprised of two series: Democratic Party activities and interests, and University of Michigan activities. The Democratic Party papers concern Ann Arbor, Washtenaw County, and state politics. Issues documented include the passage of a fair housing law in Ann Arbor, and his interest in the Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, 1964-1965.
Subjects:
Ann Arbor (Mich.); Democratic Party (Mich.); Democratic Party (Mich.). State Central Committee.; Discrimination in housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Historians--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Housing--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Michigan--Politics and government--1961-1970.; Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party.; Mississippi--Politics and government--1951-; University of Michigan. Dept. of History.; University of Michigan--Faculty.; Michigan--Politics and government--1951-
Subjects - Sound Recordings:
Democratic Party (Mich.); Weinberg, Gerhard L.; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Staebler, Neil, 1905-
Contributors:
Ferency, Zolton A., 1922-; Hart, Philip A. (Philip Aloysius), 1912-1976.; Staebler, Neil, 1905-; Swainson, John Burley, 1925-
Genre Terms:
Phonograph records.; Sound recordings.
- Democratic Party activities and interests
  - Ann Arbor Democratic Party
    - 1957-1970, 33 folders (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor Proposed Zoning Code, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Council Charter Amendment Committee papers, 1965-1967, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Ann Arbor City Council Charter Amendment Committee papers, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
  - Washtenaw County Democratic Conventions papers, undated and 1961-1970, 16 folders (Box 1)
  - Second Congressional District papers, 1962-1968, 11 folders (Box 1)
  - Livingston County Democratic Committee, 1964, 3 folders (Box 2)
  - Democratic State Central Committee papers, 1958-1967, 45 folders (Box 2)
  - Democratic State Central Committee papers, 1967-1970, 10 folders (Box 3)
  - Neil Staebler Gubernatorial Campaign, 1964 (Box 3)
  - National Committeeman Election, 1965 (Box 3)
  - Legislative Reapportionment, 1963-1965 (Box 3)
  - Constitutional Convention, 1962-1963, 5 folders (Box 3)
  - National Legislative Action Program, 1963-1967, 3 folders (Box 3)
  - Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, 1964-1965, 11 folders (Box 3)
  - Michigan Democratic Party Political Reform Commission, 1969-1970, 17 folders (Box 3)
  - Democratic Party produced phonograph record (Box 1)
    - Side 1, Hospital insurance for the aged through Social Security, 17 minutes
    - Side 2, discussion of current issues with Senator Philip Hart and Congressman-at-Large Neil Staebler at the Wayne County Democratic Women's Day program, January 25, 1964
- University of Michigan Activities
  - Minutes of L.S.&A. faculty meetings, 1959-1973 (Box 4)
  - History Department File, 1961-1971 (Box 5)
  - Library File (Box 5)
  - Extension and Adult-Education (Box 5)
  - University Senate (Box 6)
  - Senate Assembly (Box 6)
  - S.A.C.U.A. (Box 6)
  - Miscellaneous Files (Box 6)